# Jose Mari Ponce

## Full-stack Software Engineer

I'm a Software Engineer with more than 12 years of professional experience. I've been engaged in various web application architectures. My most recent technology stack is developing cloudnative applications using Vue.js, Node.js, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase and MySQL.



ponce.josemari@gmail.com

+61 39 0881383

Melbourne, Australia

ecnop.dev 📾

linkedin.com/in/ecnopdev in

twitter.com/ecnopdev

github.com/ecnopdev 🔘

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineer Singapore Press Holdings

09/2014 - Present

Singapore

Design, develop and implement cloud-native enterprise applications. Achievements/Tasks

- Migrated 8 enterprise applications to various cloudnative architectures using Vue.is, Node.is, Firebase and Google Cloud Platform.
- Implemented a suite of mobile applications for journalists used for covering big events.
- Developed a company-wide migration tool for converting Lotus Notes documents to Google Doc.
- Lead 3 SCRUM teams and facilitated sprints using JIRA.

Contact: Norman Quek - Manager - quekch@sph.com.sg

# Software Engineer

Orica Australia 07/2013 - 08/2014

**Philippines** 

Global application support for business applications built on Lotus Notes and Xpages.

Achievements/Tasks

- Closed more than 80 application support tickets where I work remotely with users from all over the world.
- Completed several major enhancements for 4 legacy systems.

Contact: Prashant Bhaysar - Supervisor prashant.bhavsar@orica.com

## **Systems Analyst**

## Sun Life of Canada Philippines

Design, develop and implement business applications using Lotus Notes and Java

Achievements/Tasks

12/2011 - 06/2013

 Lead developer in implementing the policy contract system for Sun Life Vietnam

### Software Engineer Abbott Laboratories

08/2011 - 12/2011

**Philippines** 

**Philippines** 

Design, develop and implement business applications using Lotus Notes.

## Software Engineer

Softweb Consulting Incorporated

02/2008 - 07/2011 **Philippines** Design, develop and implement business applications using Lotus Notes

Achievements/Tasks

Pioneer of Xpages and SCRUM

Contact: Glenn Liwanag - Supervisor - glennliwanag@gmail.com

#### SKILLS

**Firebase** 

Vue.js

Node.js

Google Cloud Platform

**GSuite** 

**SCRUM** 

MySQL

### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** major in Software Technology

De La Salle University - Manila

05/2000 - 04/2004

**Philippines** 

## Master of Information Systems

University of the Philippines - Open University

08/2019 - Present

**Philippines** 

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Scrum Master

Scrum Alliance

#### **CONFERENCES & COURSES**

Cloud Architecture with Google Cloud Specialization (05/2020)

Coursera

Cloud Engineering with Google Cloud Specialization (05/2020)

Coursera

#### **AWARDS**

Dean's Lister

De La Salle University - Manila

#### INTERESTS

**Table Tennis** 

**Mobile Games** 

Musical Intruments